Guide to the Carlos Bulosan Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Carlos Bulosan papers
1914-1976
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
0581
Bulosan, Carlos
4.99 cubic feet 7 boxes
3 vertical files
19 microfilm reels
3 sound cassettes
3 sound tape reels
2 CD-ROM discs
Papers of a Filipino-American author, poet, and migrant laborer
Carlos Sampayan Bulosan (c. 1911– September 11, 1956) was a Filipino American author, poet, and activist. A chronicler of the Filipino American experience in during the 1930s-early 1950s on the West Coast, he is best remembered for his semi-fictionalized autobiographical novel America Is In the Heart (1946). Though Bulosan was only 42-45 years old when he died of tuberculosis-complicated pneumonia in Seattle in 1956, he left behind a large body of poems, novels, short stories, plays, and correspondence on a wide range of interrelated topics. Bulosan’s work described the experience of growing up poor in a rural area of the Philippines, chronicling the conditions of neocolonialism after American occupation and centuries of Spanish colonialism. Bulosan’s work captures the “push” factors that drove himself his generation to the United States. Like Bulosan, they hoped to find a better future and forged resilient and adaptive communities in the face of an often-hostile and exploitative European American culture in the United States. Bulosan is remembered as a progressive anti-colonial, pro-labor, humanitarian voice by an array of communities including Asian/Pacific Islanders, organized labor, academics and intellectuals, and a wide array of social justice; ethnic; and activist communities.
Arranged in 6 accessions:
Accession No. 0581-010, Carlos Bulosan poems and writing, 1914, undated
Accession No. 0581-011, Carlos Bulosan writings, 1936, undated
Accession No. 0581-012, Carlos Bulosan papers, 1936-1976 (bulk 1948-1956)
Accession No. 0581-013, Sound cassettes about Carlos Bulosan, 1959-1960
Accession No. 0581-014, Carlos Bulosan papers, 1953
Accession No. 0581-015, Ralph Franklin postcard, 1963
Contains writings, annotated manuscripts, correspondence, taped recordings of reminscences and tributes by friends and associates, lists, publications, clippings, financial records, miscellany, ephemera, and scrapbook.
Photographs related to Carlos Bulosan can be found in the
Carlos Bulosan Photograph Collection, PH Collection 1156
it is likely that they were removed from the Carlos Bulosan Papers.
Records relating to Carlos Bulosan and the union of which he was a part, the Cannery Workers and Farm Laborers Union, Local 7.
Aurelio Bulosan papers
Cannery Workers and Farm Laborers Union Local 7 records
Cannery Workers and Farm Laborers Union, Local 7 photographs
John Caughlan papers
Cindy Domingo papers
Jean Gundlach papers
C. T. (Barry) Hatten papers
Chris D. Mensalvas papers
Chris D. Mensalvas photograph collection
Trinidad Rojo papers
Victorio A. Velasco papers
Open to all users.
Bulosan, Carlos$vArchives; Mensalvas, Chris D.,$d -1977$xInterviews; Patrick, Josephine$xInterviews; Franklin, Ralph; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.$bLocal 37 (Seattle, Wash.); Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Seattle (Wash.)$x Intellectual life$y20th century; Seattle (Wash.)$xSocial life and customs$y20th century; Filipino Americans$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vArchives; American literature$xFilipino American authors; American poetry$xFilipino American authors; Dramatists, American$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$y20th century; Filipino American theater; Filipino American authors$zWashington(State)$zSeattle; Filipino Americans$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$y20th century; Filipino Americans in literature; Political activists$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$y20th century; Correspondence; Ephemera; Financial records; Reminiscences; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Scrapbooks; Yearbooks; Migrant agricultural laborers
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor history; Literature
- Carlos Bulosan poems and writing, 1914, undated; 0581-010; 1 vertical file (11 pages)
  Photocopied poems, 1914, undated; writing, undated.
  Open to all users.
  Gift of Mary Gibson via Licerio C. Lagda, July 24, 1986.
  Originals donated to the University of the Philippines by L. Lagda.
- Carlos Bulosan writings, 1936, undated; 0581-011; 0.21 cubic feet 1 box (139 pages)
  Photocopies of writings, 1936, undated. Also an unpublished novel, "All the Conspirators" (136 pages) believed by donor to be Bulosan's and given to him by J. Patrick of Seattle, Washington.
  Gift of L.C. Lagda, November 12, 1986.
- Carlos Bulosan papers, 1936-1976, undated; 1948-1956; 0581-012; 4.65 cubic ft. 6 boxes; 9 negative microfilm reels,10 positive microfilm reels; 3 sound tape reels
  Arranged by type of record.
  Contains writings, annotated manuscripts, correspondence, taped recordings of reminscences and tributes by friends and associates, lists, publications, clippings, financial records, miscellany, ephemera, scrapbook.
  Some of the writings and manuscripts are microfilm copies of originals either from this collection or owned by other individuals or repositories. The bulk of the collection is typed, annotated manuscripts, or correspondence.
  Some of the Bulosan papers are also available on microfilm.
  View selections from this collection in digital format
  Listening equipment necessary for 7-inch reel-to-reel audio tapes and cassette audio tapes. Microfilm reader necessary to view microfilm. Contact Special Collections for details.
  The bulk of the papers in this accession was collected by the Bulosan Manuscript Committee in 1959.
  - Writings
    - Prose
      - Biographical sketch for 20th century authors, undated (Box-folder 1/1)
      - "The cry and the dedication", undated; circa 250 pages (Box-folder 1/2)
      - "The cry and the dedication", undated; circa 250 pages (Box-folder 1/3)
      - "A rich man in the family", undated; 9 pages (Box-folder 1/4)
      - "The power of music", undated; 11 pages (Box-folder 1/5)
      - "Wisdom of Uncle Sator", undated; 19 pages (Box-folder 1/6)
      - "Betrayal of Uncle Soyoc", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 1/7)
      - "Homecoming of Uncle Manuel", undated; 7 pages (Box-folder 1/8)
      - "A servant in the house", undated; 10 pages (Box-folder 1/9)
      - "Dinner with a king", undated; 9 pages, with two different copies of page 67 (Box-folder 1/10)
      - "The story of creation", undated; 100 pages (Box-folder 1/11)
      - "A trip to Baguio", undated; 16 pages (Box-folder 1/12)
      - "Marriage of Cousin Pedro", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 1/13)
      - "Be American", undated; 9 pages (Box-folder 1/14)
      - "Bandit and the tax collector", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 1/15)
      - "The betrayal of Uncle Roman", undated; 11 pages (Box-folder 1/16)
      - "Son of Uncle Sator", undated; 10 pages (Box-folder 1/17)
      - "I am not a laughing man", undated; 7 pages (Box-folder 1/18)
      - "My first day in America", undated; 3 pages (Box-folder 1/19)
      - "The summer of beautiful music", undated; 7 pages (Box-folder 1/20)
      - "Return of the amorous ghost", undated; 10 pages (Box-folder 1/21)
      - "Lonesome mermaid", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 1/22)
      - "The great lover", undated; 10 pages (Box-folder 1/23)
      - "Springtime of my father", undated; 7 pages (Box-folder 1/24)
      - "Now long shadows were falling", undated; 61 pages (Box-folder 1/25)
      - "The big convention", undated; 26 pages (Box-folder 1/26)
      - "The amorous ghost came to town", undated; 9 pages (Box-folder 1/27)
      - "The beer drinkers", undated; 9 pages (Box-folder 1/28)
      - "Heart of darkness", undated; 4 pages (Box-folder 1/29)
      - "Tales from the old country", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 1/30)
      - "Really, a ghost?", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 1/31)
      - "The rooster's egg", undated; 14 pages (Box-folder 1/32)
      - "Unfinished portrait", undated; 9 pages (Box-folder 1/33)
      - "Cat in the rain", undated; 12 pages (Box-folder 1/34)
      - "The younger sister", undated; 18 pages (Box-folder 1/35)
      - "I don't know why", undated; 7 pages (Box-folder 1/36)
      - "My brother Joey", undated; 17 pages (Box-folder 2/1)
      - "The stolen violin", undated; 11 pages (Box-folder 2/2)
      - "The night reveals", undated; 12 pages (Box-folder 2/3)
      - "Death of an author", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 2/4)
      - "I should have stood in bed", undated; 13 pages (Box-folder 2/5)
      - "Miracle by the sea", undated; 4 pages (Box-folder 2/6)
      - "The thief", undated; 12 pages (Box-folder 2/7)
      - "The glorious day", undated; 9 pages (Box-folder 2/8)
      - "Americano from Luzon", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 2/9)
      - "Odyssey of Constantia Drake", undated; 10 pages (Box-folder 2/10)
      - "Romance of Magno Rubio", undated; 20 pages (Box-folder 2/11)
      - "We laugh a little", undated; 17 pages (Box-folder 2/12)
      - "The hairline of Pantaleon Cordalles Moradoro", undated; 20 pages (Box-folder 2/13)
      - "The worldbeaters", undated; 22 pages (Box-folder 2/14)
      - "The tall white horse", undated; 19 pages (Box-folder 2/15)
      - "The angel in Santo Domingo", undated; 22 pages (Box-folder 2/16)
      - "A city in the sky", undated; 26 pages (Box-folder 2/17)
      - "How my brother Leon brought home a wife and other Philippine stories," edited by Leopoldo Y. Yabes and Carlos Bulosan, undated; circa 600 pages (Box-folder 2/18)
      - "Cry Away the Years", undated (Box-folder 3/1)
      - "In Search of America", undated (Box-folder 3/2)
      - "Sammy Cook's Shoeshine Box", undated (Box-folder 3/2)
      - "A Story of Faith", undated (Box-folder 3/2)
      - "A Virgin for Cousin Pedro and Other Tales of Luzon", undated; 181 pages (Box-folder 3/3-7)
        For preservation, some pages have been photocopied and the originals are stored in Vertical File 2731.
      - "As Long as the Grass Shall Grow", undated (Box-folder 3/8)
      - "The Betrayal of Uncle Roman", undated; 11 pages (Box-folder 3/9)
      - "Death of a Rich Man", undated; 10 pages (Box-folder 3/10)
      - "The Return of Uncle Sator", undated; 9 pages (Box-folder 3/11)
      - "The Son of Uncle Sator", undated; 10 pages (Box-folder 3/12)
      - "A Trip to Bagvio", undated; 16 pages (Box-folder 3/13)
      - "The Ugly Hunter and the Beautiful Woman and Other Tales", undated; 13 pages (Box-folder 3/14)
      - "The Filipino Houseboy", undated; 12 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "In Manila: A Fragment", undated; 6 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "Girl on the Beach", undated; 12 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "What Happened Before", undated; 5 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "One Winter Night", undated; 7 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "Even the Rain Remembers", undated; 16 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "My Brother's Marriage", undated; 3 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "The Genius", undated; 14 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "Cabin in the Orchard", undated; 6 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "My Filipino Houseboy", undated; 12 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "My Father Goes to Court", undated; 6 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "The Little Brown Mouse", undated; 14 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "Nightfall", undated; 9 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "Sammy Cooke's Shoeshine Box", undated; 8 pages (Box-folder 3/15)
      - "How my stories were written", undated; 1 item (Box-folder 3/16)
      - Fragments, undated; 2 items (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Poems
      - "I Want the Wide American Earth", undated; 25 autographed copies (Box-folder 3/17)
      - "Adoration", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Allan", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Dark Moment", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Desire", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Elegy for Mary Ann", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Epitaph", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Exits and Entrances for Our Time", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "For Marjorie", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Gift", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "I saw your face", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "In the moonlight", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Interlude" (two versions), undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "A Little Poem", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Marching", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "My new room", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Okaboji Lake - Iowa", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Our lives conflicted towards the end", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Passage from life", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "A song of freedom", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Testament", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "To Adam, with thanks", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Who was it that loved a tree", undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - Fragment, undated (Box-folder 3/18)
      - "Exits and Entrances for Our Time", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "For Chris - on his birthday", 1954 (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "The Good Life: What Did I Know", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "I met her in the tall summertime", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "I write a poem about you pen", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "Into the world I walk free", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "A Midnight Song", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "My Country/My Street", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "The Oak Tree", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "The Surrounded", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "You shall know my sons", undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - Fragment, undated (Box-folder 3/19)
      - "Another Legend", undated (Box-folder 3/20)
      - "A Darkness. A Snowfall. A Rain.", undated (Box-folder 3/20)
      - "Landscape With a Bottle", undated (Box-folder 3/20)
      - "Last Poem", undated (Box-folder 3/20)
      - "You will grow old together", undated (Box-folder 3/20)
      - Drafts, undated; approximately 19 pages (Box-folder 3/21)
      - "A Hill. A House. And Love.", undated; 1954 (Box-folder 3/22)
      - "All Summer", 1954 (Box-folder 3/22)
      - "Another April", 1954 (Box-folder 3/22)
      - "Another Letter to J. II", 1954; 2 pages (Box-folder 3/22)
      - "Aha! or The Face of Love", undated; 2 pages (Box-folder 3/22)
      - "Conversation at Midnight", undated (Box-folder 3/23)
      - "Discovery of a Memory", 1954 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - "Exits and Entrances for Our Time", 1954 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - "In Memory and the Flags Are There", undated (Box-folder 3/23)
      - "In Remembrance", 1954 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - "I Want the Rich Philippine Earth", 1953; 3 pages (Box-folder 3/24)
      - "Lament For a Sleeping Child", undated (Box-folder 3/24)
      - "Landscape", undated (Box-folder 3/24)
      - "Letter to T." (unfinished), undated; 2 pages (Box-folder 3/25)
      - "The Living Seed", undated (Box-folder 3/25)
      - "Love Song (Recuerdo for Josephine)", undated; 2 pages (Box-folder 3/25)
      - "My Country and My Street", 1955 (Box-folder 3/26)
      - "The Oak Leaf", undated (Box-folder 3/26)
      - "On a Day in Seattle", undated (Box-folder 3/26)
      - "Once Again I Will Tell You", undated; 2 pages (Box-folder 3/26)
      - "On that Day", undated (Box-folder 3/26)
      - "My New Room (For Chris and Irene)", 1955 (Box-folder 3/27)
      - "My Sister, My Bride", undated; 2 pages (Box-folder 3/27)
      - "A New Year Letter", 1954 (Box-folder 3/27)
      - "II. October 31, 1954", circa 1954; 3 pages (Box-folder 3/27)
      - "Poem to Be Whispered", undated (Box-folder 3/28)
      - "Prologue", undated (Box-folder 3/28)
      - "Remembrance: I", undated (Box-folder 3/28)
      - "Remembrance: II", undated (Box-folder 3/28)
      - "Song for Chris Mensalves' Birthday", 1954 (Box-folder 3/29)
      - "The Song I Sing at Midnight", 1953; 2 pages each, 2 copies (Box-folder 3/29)
      - "The Vaulted Wall", undated (Box-folder 3/30)
      - "A Walk Through the Woods", undated (Box-folder 3/30)
      - "The Young Ones", undated (Box-folder 3/30)
      - Untitled poems, undated; 2 pages (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Poems "compiled for Chris and Irene"
      - "When I was a Little Boy: A Dream", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "The Bee and the Rose", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "When the Knife Cut You", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "I Cannot Lose You", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "White Rose, Wild Rose, Lost Rose", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "When You Were a Little Girl", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Dark Moment", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "The Blue Sky", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Testament", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Little Elegy", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Fear", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Desire", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "My Country", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Growth", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Is It a Poem", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Silence", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "My Mother", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "But Eyes", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Cancione Maldita", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Land of the Morning", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Can I Love You", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Of Love and Hate", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Unfinished Letter", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Will You be Men When You Grow Up", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "There is only you in the poem", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "What Would You Do", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Adoration", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "My People", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "A Song of Freedom", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Gift", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Marching", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "In the Moonlight", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Forever", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Little Song", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "When I Was a Little Boy: A Reality", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Praise and Warning", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "A Little Poem", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Mother and Child", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Testament of Earth", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "A Bright Star", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Miracle of Spring", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Passage from Life", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Land of Beauty", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Beautiful Boy", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Two Eternities", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Now You are Still", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "Only a Bird", undated (Box-folder 4/1)
      - "The Dream", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Morning Song", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "The Morning is Still Dark", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "About Socrates", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "My Sisters in the Garden", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Anticipation and Contemplation", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Silence", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Prayer for the Beloved Dead", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Where My Love Lies", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "What Is a Poet?", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "The Consolation of Ambiguity", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Dark Moment", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "The Map of Life", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Needing No Time", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Tale of the Sleeping Dog" (2 copies), undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Theseus", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "Letter to Fred, My Nephew", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
      - "My Father Was a Working Man", undated (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Plays
      - The Masquerade Ball: A New Year's Eve Legend, undated (Box-folder 4/3)
      - The Wall, undated (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Jose Rizal - excerpt, undated (Box-folder 4/4)
        In verse.
      - Jose Rizal, undated (Box-folder 4/5)
      - Jose Rizal - fragments, undated; 10 pages (Box-folder 4/6)
      - The Big Silver Dollar undated (Box-folder 4/7)
      - The Worldbeaters undated (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Correspondence
    - General Correspondence
      - Carlos Bulosan, 1948, 1955, undated; 6 items (Box-folder 4/8)
      - Carlos Bulosan to Mary Gibson, 1953 May 14; 5 items (Box-folder 4/9)
        Includes 4 pages of verses.
      - Bulosan Manuscript Committee, 1959, 1960; 5 items (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Bauer, Harry C., 1956; 8 items (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Bulosan, Marjorie, 1949, 1950-1953; 4 items (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, International, Local 7-C, 1952; 2 items (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Josephine Patrick to Washington State Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born, 1953 April 23; 1 item (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Incoming letters
      - Bulosan, Aurelio, 1948; 4 items (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Bulosan, Marjorie Patton, 1953, undated; 6 items (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Committee to Sponsor (Luis) Taruc's Autobiography, 1953; 1 item (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Harcourt, Brace and Company, Publishers, New York, 1955; 1 item (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Kunkel, Donald R., 1953; 1 item (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Lieber, Maxin, 1948; 1 item (Box-folder 4/13)
      - The Nation, 1953; 1 item (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Saunders, Marion, 1949; 1 item (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Wilson (H. W.) Company, publishers, New York, 1953; 1 item (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Wolf, Harriet, 1948-1949; 5 items (Box-folder 4/13)
      - 1948-1956, 8 items (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Outgoing letters
      - undated, 1 item (Box-folder 4/15)
      - 1947-1955, 5 items (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Of Others Concerning the Bulosan Manuscripts Collection, undated (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Financial records
    - 1954-1955, 4 items (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1950; 1 item (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1949; 1 item (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Lists
    - undated, 3 items (Box-folder 4/20)
    - The Carlos Bulosan Fund, undated; 1 item (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Publications
    - International Longshoremen’s and Warehousemen's Union, Cannery Workers, Local 37, Edited by Bulosan, circa 1950 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - International Longshoremen’s and Warehousemen's Union, Cannery Workers, Local 37, Edited by Bulosan, 1952; 1 item (Box-folder 4/23)
    - Common Ground, 1949; 1 item (Box-folder 4/24)
      Includes prose, "As Long as the Grass Shall Grow."
    - Frontier and Midland, 1936; 1 item (Box-folder 4/24)
      Includes poem "At Winter Evening."
    - Saturday Evening Post - "The Four Freedoms", 1943; 1 item (Box:oversize 6)
  - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 4/25-26)
  - Sound recordings, undated; 3 reel-to-reel tapes
    Cassette listening copies available in folder 5/3 of Accession No.0581-013.
    - Reminiscences - Bulosan's later years by Josephine Patrick, Berry Hatton, Red Gibbs, 1966; 1 item (Box-folder 4/27)
    - Reminiscences -- by Chris Mensalvas, 1959; 1 item (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Tribute to Carlos Bulosan by friends and associates, 1974; 1 item (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Interviews, 1959, 1960; Cassette tapes (Box-folder 5/3)
      Duplicates of interviews of November 19, 1959 and June 19, 1960.
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 6 items (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Notes, undated; 1 item (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Ephemera, 1976; 3 items (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Biographical and bibliographical information, undated (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Speeches and writings of others
    - Poem - "Bulosan New" by Alvaro Cardona-Hine, undated (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Unpublished manuscript by Trinidad A. Rojo, circa 1946 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Ethnic Cultural Center Production Items, undated (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box:oversize 6)
  - Microfilm collection
    - Writings of Bulosan
      - Play in Verse - Jose Rizal (Reel 1)
      - Poems
        - "July 5, 1953', undated (Reel 1)
        - "The Oak Tree", undated (Reel 1)